Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be bringing you a great lesson that's talking about a bank
今天我们要给大家带来一堂很棒的课，讲的是银行
robbery.
抢劫。
Yes, and this is an important lesson for all of our future bank robbers out there.
是的，这对我们所有未来的银行劫匪来说是一堂重要的课。
Yeah, we are going to teach you some words that you would use for planning a bank robbery,
没错，我们会教你们一些用于策划银行抢劫的词汇，
but you can apply them to other situations, hopefully not.
但你们也可以把它们用在其他场合，希望不是这样。
Yeah, I hope you apply them to other situations.
是啊，我希望你们用在其他场合。
Hopefully you won't rob a bank.
希望你们不会去抢银行。
We don't want to be responsible for any crimes you can commit.
我们可不想为你们可能犯下的罪行负责。
Yes.
是的。
Alright, so why don't we start by looking at some of the vocabulary in Vocabulary Preview.
好了，那我们不如先看看“词汇预览”里的一些词汇。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
We have one word for you today that you'll hear in the dialogue and it is filling in.
今天我们有一个词，你们会在对话中听到，就是“filling in”。
Filling in.
Filling in。
So to fill in for somebody, right?
所以是“fill in for somebody”，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
That means that you are replacing them.
意思是你在代替他们。
Yes.
是的。
So if Marco can't host the show today, maybe Dany will fill in.
所以如果Marco今天不能主持节目，也许Dany会来顶替。
Okay, so to take the place of someone.
好的，就是代替某人的位置。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright.
好的。
Okay, so now let's listen to our dialogue.
好了，那我们现在来听对话。
Let's listen to this bank robbery and let's see what happens.
我们来听听这个银行抢劫案，看看会发生什么。
Alright, so this is what we're going to do.
好的，这就是我们要做的。
I've carefully mapped this out, so don't screw it up.
我仔细规划好了，所以别搞砸了。
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go to the bank wearing these uniforms.
兔子先生，你和狐狸先生穿上这些制服去银行。
We've managed to get replicas of the one the guards wear for when they pick up the money.
我们搞到了警卫取钱时穿的制服的复制品。
Got it.
明白了。
No problem, boss.
没问题，老大。
When you get inside, tell them that you're filling in for Carl and Tom and say that they're
进去后，告诉他们你们是来顶替Carl和Tom的，并说他们
on another route today.
今天在另一条路线上。
Don't lose your cool.
别慌。
Just act natural.
自然点就行。
What if they want to call and confirm?
如果他们想打电话确认呢？
You let them.
让他们打。
What?
什么？
Don't worry.
别担心。
We have the phones tapped, so the call will be passed through to me and I'll pretend to
我们窃听了电话，所以电话会转接到我这里，我会假装
be the transport company.
是运输公司。
You're so clever, boss.
老大，你真聪明。
Okay, shut up.
好了，闭嘴。
Only take as much money as you can fit in these bags.
只拿能装进这些袋子的钱。
Don't get greedy.
别贪心。
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Let's go.
走吧。
Well, it sounds like a pretty interesting plan.
嗯，听起来是个挺有趣的计划。
It does sound like a plan.
听起来确实像个计划。
Do you think it'll work?
你觉得会成功吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I guess we'll have to maybe talk a little bit about that later.
我想我们可能得晚点再讨论一下。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是啊。
Let's take a look at the language that we saw in Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”里看到的语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, we heard five really great words in this dialogue that I'd like to look at now
好的，我们在对话中听到了五个很棒的词，现在我想在
in Language Takeaway.
“语言要点”里看看它们。
So let's go to the first one.
那我们来看第一个。
Now we heard the boss say that they got replicas of the uniforms.
我们听到老大说他们搞到了制服的复制品。
Right, replicas.
对，replicas。
Replicas.
Replicas。
So this is really easy.
这很简单。
Something that's a replica is a copy.
复制品就是仿制品。
Exactly.
没错。
Right?
对吧？
So for example, in Las Vegas, there's a replica of the Eiffel Tower of Paris.
比如，在拉斯维加斯，有一个巴黎埃菲尔铁塔的复制品。
Yes.
是的。
Actually, I lived in a small city where there was also a replica of the Eiffel Tower.
实际上，我住在一个小城市，那里也有一个埃菲尔铁塔的复制品。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, in France.
是啊，在法国。
That is kind of weird.
那有点奇怪。
Well, there are a lot of replicas.
嗯，有很多复制品。
Even now on the street, maybe you can see replica watches, right?
甚至现在街上，你可能会看到仿制手表，对吧？
That supposedly are Rolex, but they're not.
那些号称是劳力士，但并不是。
And many, many other things.
还有很多很多其他东西。
So, copies.
所以，就是仿制品。
Yes.
是的。
Not the real thing.
不是真品。
All right, so let's take a look at the next word.
好的，那我们来看下一个词。
Tapped.
Tapped。
We have the phones tapped.
我们窃听了电话。
Tapped.
Tapped。
So if you tap someone's phone, you do something to the telephone line so that you can hear
所以如果你窃听某人的电话，你对电话线做了手脚，这样你就能听到
their conversations, right?
他们的对话，对吧？
Right.
对。
And actually, the police do this sometimes, right?
实际上，警察有时会这么做，对吧？
Right.
对。
You see it in movies all the time.
你在电影里经常看到。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
You connect a wire to the phone so you can listen to the conversation.
你把一根线接到电话上，这样就能听到对话。
Exactly.
没错。
So, you tap the telephone line.
所以，你窃听了电话线。
So in our dialogue, they tapped the bank's phone, right?
所以在我们的对话中，他们窃听了银行的电话，对吧？
And he said if they make a call, he will patch the call through to him.
他说如果他们打电话，他会把电话转接给他。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
So, patch through.
所以，patch through。
Patch through.
Patch through。
Yeah, patch a call through.
是啊，转接电话。
Patch through.
Patch through。
And we use this today.
我们今天也用这个词。
Yeah.
是啊。
Like if you call an office, right?
比如你打电话到办公室，对吧？
And you say, oh, can you patch me through to Carol?
你说，哦，你能帮我转接给Carol吗？
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
So, can you connect me to another phone line?
所以，你能把我连接到另一条电话线吗？
Connect me.
连接我。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
Now, let's take a look at our next words.
现在，我们来看下一个词。
Clever.
Clever。
Yes, the boss is very clever.
是的，老大很聪明。
The boss is very clever.
老大很聪明。
All right.
好的。
So if you're clever, you're...
所以如果你clever，你就是……
You're smart.
你很聪明。
Yeah.
是啊。
You're really smart.
你真的很聪明。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right.
对。
So, you're clever and this is a clever plan.
所以，你很聪明，这是个聪明的计划。
Clever plan.
聪明的计划。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, let's take a look at our last word.
现在，我们来看最后一个词。
Don't be greedy.
别贪心。
Greedy.
Greedy。
To be greedy is a bad thing.
贪心是件坏事。
Right.
对。
You want everything.
你什么都想要。
You want everything for you.
你什么都想占为己有。
Yes.
是的。
You don't share.
你不分享。
Yes.
是的。
So, like at lunch today, when you had that cake.
比如，今天午餐时，你吃了那块蛋糕。
And I didn't share?
我没分享吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
I was very greedy?
我很贪心吗？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Yes.
是的。
With food, I am greedy.
在食物方面，我很贪心。
All right.
好的。
So, these are some great words.
所以，这些都是很棒的词。
And I think, you know, if we listen to the dialogue another time, a little bit more slowly,
我想，如果我们再听一遍对话，稍微慢一点，
we'll be able to hear them a little bit better.
我们就能更好地听到它们。
All right.
好的。
So this is what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的。
I've carefully mapped this out.
我仔细规划好了。
So don't screw it up.
所以别搞砸了。
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go into the bank wearing these uniforms.
兔子先生，你和狐狸先生穿上这些制服去银行。
We've managed to get replicas of the one the guards wear when they pick up the money.
我们搞到了警卫取钱时穿的制服的复制品。
Got it.
明白了。
No problem, boss.
没问题，老大。
When you get inside, tell them that you're filling in for Carl and Tom and say that they're
进去后，告诉他们你们是来顶替Carl和Tom的，并说他们
on another route today.
今天在另一条路线上。
Don't lose your cool.
别慌。
Just act natural.
自然点就行。
What if they want to call and conform?
如果他们想打电话确认呢？
You let them.
让他们打。
What?
什么？
Don't worry.
别担心。
We have the phones tapped.
我们窃听了电话。
So the call will be patched through to me.
所以电话会转接到我这里。
And I'll pretend to be the transport company.
我会假装是运输公司。
You're so clever, boss.
老大，你真聪明。
Okay, shut up.
好了，闭嘴。
Only take as much money as you can fit into these bags.
只拿能装进这些袋子的钱。
Don't get greedy.
别贪心。
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Let's go.
走吧。
Okay, so now we understand these words that we talked about in Language Takeaway.
好了，现在我们理解了“语言要点”里讨论的这些词。
So now let's take a look at some of these great phrases in Fluency Builder.
那现在我们来看看“流利度构建”里的一些好短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
We've got three phrases for you here.
我们这里有三个短语。
And these are all phrases you might use when you're planning something.
这些都是在计划某事时可能用到的短语。
So the first one, mapped out.
第一个，mapped out。
I've carefully mapped this out.
我仔细规划好了。
Mapped out.
Mapped out。
To map out.
To map out。
So when you map something out, what do you do?
所以当你map something out时，你做什么？
Well, you literally create a plan.
嗯，你字面上制定一个计划。
You draw a map of what you're going to do.
你画一张你要做什么的路线图。
So here, is it only for like travel or?
所以这里，它只用于旅行之类的吗？
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
It's like, for example, if we're starting a new project in the company, you can map
比如，如果我们在公司启动一个新项目，你可以规划
out the project, what you're going to do this month, next month.
这个项目，这个月、下个月要做什么。
So it's a plan.
所以它是一个计划。
So you draw every step in the plan.
所以你画出计划中的每一步。
Every step, right.
每一步，对。
So you said, well, I've mapped out this plan for a new project.
所以你说，嗯，我为新项目规划好了这个计划。
Okay, interesting word.
好的，一个有趣的词。
I think we should hear some examples of how it's used.
我觉得我们应该听一些它用法的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
So I have the future all mapped out.
所以我已经把未来都规划好了。
Well, you'll get a job as a waiter, then we'll get married.
嗯，你会先当个服务员，然后我们结婚。
And two years later, we'll start having kids.
两年后，我们开始要孩子。
Example two.
例子二。
We're mapping out the marketing plan at the meeting today.
我们今天在会议上规划营销方案。
Example three.
例子三。
Okay, I've mapped out our trip and it should take about 10 hours.
好的，我已经规划好了我们的行程，大概需要10个小时。
All right, so mapped out.
好了，所以“mapped out”这个词。
Really, really clear now.
现在非常清楚了。
Let's take a look at our next word.
我们来看看下一个词。
All right, so if you've mapped out a plan, you don't want to screw it up.
好的，如果你已经规划好了一个计划，你就不想搞砸它。
Right, screw it up.
对，“screw it up”。
Screw it up.
搞砸它。
Or screw up.
或者“screw up”。
Yep.
是的。
So to screw something up means that you made a mistake on something.
所以“screw something up”意思是你在某件事上犯了错。
Or you did something wrong.
或者你做错了什么。
You did it wrong.
你做错了。
Yep.
是的。
Okay, so for example, if I'm taking an exam and I make a mistake, I screwed up on the
好的，比如，如果我参加考试犯了错，我就在考试中搞砸了。
exam.
考试。
Exactly.
没错。
Or for example, here, when we're recording, Marco and I make mistakes a lot.
或者比如，在这里录音时，马可和我经常犯错。
Maybe more me than Marco.
可能我比马可犯得更多。
We always screw up.
我们总是搞砸。
Yeah.
是啊。
Exactly.
没错。
So to make a mistake, it's a really informal word, but very, very common.
所以“犯错”这个词很口语化，但非常非常常用。
Yeah.
是啊。
And you know, it sounds really, really natural when people use this.
你知道，当人们用这个词时，听起来非常自然。
All right, so now let's take a look at our last word.
好了，现在我们来看看最后一个词。
Lose your cool.
失去冷静。
Don't lose your cool.
别失去冷静。
So what is this, to lose your cool?
那么“失去冷静”是什么意思？
It's a weird expression.
这是个奇怪的表达。
Why don't we just give you an example of a person that loses his or her cool.
不如我们直接给你举个例子，看看一个人失去冷静的样子。
What do you mean you're not ready to go?
你什么意思，你还没准备好出发？
It's time to go.
该走了。
We have to go now.
我们现在就得走。
Boninato!
博尼纳托！
We were supposed to leave!
我们本来应该出发了！
Punietta, now we're sitting here again.
普尼埃塔，现在我们又坐在这儿了。
I'm going to wait for you.
我要等你。
Boninam!
博尼纳姆！
Okay, so basically, you lose your temper.
好的，基本上就是，你发脾气了。
You become irritated.
你变得烦躁。
You lose control of your emotions.
你控制不住自己的情绪。
Right.
对。
So Marco, when you lose your cool, is it always that you get angry?
那么马可，当你失去冷静时，总是生气吗？
You don't always get angry.
不总是生气。
Maybe you get irritated or impatient.
可能你会变得烦躁或不耐烦。
Or even nervous.
甚至紧张。
Nervous.
紧张。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right?
对吧？
So basically, you're not in control of your emotions.
所以基本上，你控制不住自己的情绪。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay, so we've looked at a lot of great phrases, a lot of great words.
好的，我们看了很多很棒的短语和词汇。
So we can listen to our dialogue now for the third time, and then we'll come back and talk
现在我们可以第三次听对话，然后回来讨论这起银行抢劫案。
about this bank robbery business.
银行抢劫案。
All right, so this is what we're going to do.
好的，这就是我们要做的。
I've carefully mapped this out, so don't screw it up.
我仔细规划好了，别搞砸了。
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go to the bank wearing these uniforms.
兔子先生，你和狐狸先生穿上这些制服去银行。
We've managed to get replicas of the one the guards wear for when they pick up the money.
我们弄到了警卫取钱时穿的制服复制品。
Got it.
明白了。
No problem, boss.
没问题，老大。
When you get inside, tell them that you're filling in for Carl and Tom, and say that
进去后，告诉他们你们是替卡尔和汤姆的班，就说他们今天走另一条路线。
they're on another route today.
另一条路线。
Don't lose your cool.
别失去冷静。
Just act natural.
自然点就行。
What if they want to call and confirm?
如果他们想打电话确认呢？
You let them.
让他们打。
What?
什么？
Don't worry.
别担心。
We have the phones tapped, so the call will be patched through to me, and I'll pretend
我们监听了电话，所以电话会转接到我这里，我会假装是运输公司。
to be the transport company.
运输公司。
You're so clever, boss.
老大，你真聪明。
Okay, shut up.
好了，闭嘴。
Only take as much money as you can fit in these bags.
只拿能装进这些袋子的钱。
Don't get greedy.
别贪心。
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Let's go.
走吧。
So there's a lot of movies about bank robberies, but obviously they happen in real life.
关于银行抢劫的电影很多，但显然现实中也会发生。
So this dialogue is actually based on real events, right?
所以这段对话实际上是基于真实事件，对吧？
Yeah, this actually happened in real life, and so it's actually a very creative and nonviolent
是啊，这确实在现实中发生过，而且是一种非常有创意且非暴力的抢劫银行方式。
way of robbing a bank.
抢劫银行的方式。
Okay, so what happened?
好的，那发生了什么？
Basically, this guy went to a bank dressed up as one of those security guards that transport
基本上，这个人打扮成那种把钱从银行运到另一个安全地点的保安。
the money from the bank to another safe place.
把钱从银行运到另一个安全地点。
He had fake credentials or replica credentials.
他有假证件或复制证件。
So fake ID.
所以是假身份证。
Yeah, he had a replica of the uniform.
是啊，他有一套制服的复制品。
And he walked in, he took all these bags, him and his partner, and they took him to
然后他走进去，他和他的搭档拿了所有袋子，把他们带到卡车旁开走了。
the truck and drove off.
开走了。
The bank didn't realize that they had been robbed.
银行没意识到他们被抢了。
They thought it was a routine thing.
他们以为这是例行公事。
Three or four hours later, the real security guard shows up.
三四个小时后，真正的保安出现了。
They were long gone, and they still can't find them.
他们早就跑远了，而且至今还没找到他们。
Really?
真的吗？
So a very clever plan.
所以是个非常聪明的计划。
Very clever and very effective.
非常聪明且非常有效。
I think they stole over half a million dollars.
我想他们偷了超过五十万美元。
Okay, well guys, don't try this at home.
好了，各位，别在家尝试这个。
Don't try this at home, but real life, real English, right?
别在家尝试这个，但真实生活，真实英语，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so come to our website, leave your questions and comments.
好的，所以来我们的网站，留下你的问题和评论。
Tell us what you think will happen with these guys.
告诉我们你觉得这些人会怎么样。
Do you think they'll be successful?
你觉得他们会成功吗？
Do you think they'll get caught?
你觉得他们会被抓住吗？
Yeah, they might end up in jail.
是啊，他们可能最终会进监狱。
Maybe somebody will lose their cool and get caught, right?
也许有人会失去冷静然后被抓，对吧？
Well thanks for listening guys, and until next time, goodbye.
好了，感谢收听，各位，下次再见，拜拜。